- CIAO TERRONI! (SOUTHERNER)
- HOW'S IT GOING?
- I REMEMBER YOU
- YOU ARRIVED BY TRAIN
- AND IN CARS
- FULL OF CARDBOARD SUITCASES
- YOU GOT OUT IN PADOVA
- BUT THEN YOU SCATTERED
- AROUND HERE TO THE VILLAGES
- YOU STOOD IN FRONT OF TOWN HALL
- SCREAMING
- SCREAMING "GIVE US A HOUSE!"
- AND NOT JUST 35 FUCKING EUROS...
- ...A HOUSE...
- ALWAYS TALKING ABOUT RIGHTS
- BUT ABOUT DUTY...NEVER
- "BUT WE CAME TO WORK!"
- NOT, HOWEVER, TRUE
- YOU CAME TO DO FUCK ALL
- BECAUSE IL TERRONE
- BECAUSE IL TERRONE, TINY
- BECAUSE' IL TERRONE, TINY, DARK,
- BECAUSE' IL TERRONE, TINY, DARK, HAIRY
- DOESN'T WANT TO DO ANYTHING
- THE FEW TIMES YOU ENDED UP IN A FACTORY
- AS SOON AS YOU CLOCKED OUT, IT WAS FREE TIME
- YOU WENT AND PLAYED CARDS
- WE NORTHERNERS
- WHEN WE FINISHED FACTORY HOURS WE WORKED OUR FIELDS
- DI GIANGI
- RIZZO
- RUSSO
- ESPOSITO
- THOSE WERE THE NAMES
- YOU CAME TO LIVE IN THE PROJECTS
- AND SPENT YOUR TIME BUSTING OUR BALLS
- BULLYING US IN THE SCHOOL BATHROOMS
- OR AT THE TOWN FAIR
- WHERE YOU WERE THE MINORITY
- ALLIED WITH THE GYPSIES
- SO WE COULDN'T EVEN
WALK AROUND TOWN GATHERINGS IN PEACE
- BUT WE WERE IN OUR HOME
- AND WE CALLED YOU TERRONI
- WE PRAYED THAT VESUVIUS WOULD ERUPT
- OUR SCHOOLTEACHER TAUGHT US
- THE LION OF VENICE WILL FINISH OFF IL TERRONE
- AND EVERYONE LAUGHED
- EVEN AT THE FIRST MEETING OF THE LEAGUE THEY SAID
- IN 1979
- HAIL THE LION WHO WILL FINISH OFF IL TERRONE
- YOU TRULY DISGUSTED US
- AND YOU DISGUSTED YOURSELVES TOO EH?
- OTHERWISE WHY ELSE
- WHY ELSE WOULD YOU TRY TO SPEAK IN OUR DIALECT
- AND YOU MANGLED IT
- "BY GOD IT'S BEEN TWENTY-FIVE YEARS
THAT I DONE LIVE HERE. I BE MORE NORTHERNER THAN YOU!"
- HOW MUCH YOU DISGUSTED US?
- AND WHENEVER THERE WAS A CRIME/b>
- YOU LOOKED IN THE PAPERS AND IT WAS ALWAYS
- A DI GIANGI,
- A DI GIANGI, A RUSSO
- A DI GIANGI, A RUSSO, A ESPOSITO
- MY GRAN WHO READ THE PAPERS ALWAYS SAID
- "YOU SEE?! IT'S THOSE SOUTHERNERS!"
- BECAUSE ONLY THEIR THUGS COME UP HERE TO THE NORTH
- ONLY THE CRIMINALS COME HERE
- THEIR GOOD PEOPLE DON'T COME
- THE NOBLE OF PALERMO
- THE JUDGE FROM NAPLES
- THEY STAYED HOME
- HERE WE GOT ONLY THE DREGS
- AND WHEN SOMEONE TRIED TO SAY
- "EH BUT DOWN THERE THERE'S THE MAFIA"
- EXACTLY!
- THUGS AND COWARDS
- YOU COULDN'T EVEN STAY HOME/b>
TO FIGHT THE MAFIA
- YOU COME HERE TO DO FUCK ALL
- SURE, YEAH. 'S ALL GOOD.
ONCE AND A WHILE ONE OF YOU IS OK
- MY GRAN ALWAYS SAID
- "THAT ONE THERE IS FROM NAPLES
- BUT HE'S A GOOD PERSON"
- YOU DISGUSTED US
- BUT ONE OR TWO OF YOU WERE OK
- LIKE WHEN
- THAT NEGRO WAS ELECTED
TO THE SENATE FOR THE LEAGUE
(LAUGHS)
- BECAUSE YOU DISGUSTED US SO
- UNTIL THE MIRACLE HAPPENED
- NOT SO LONG AGO
- WHEN WE DID THE REFERENDUM
ON INDEPENDENCE FOR THE NORTH
- WE WERE STILL DEBATING
WHO WAS TERONNI OR NOT
- WHO WAS IN AND WHO WAS OUT
- BUT SUDDENLY INSTEAD
- ARRIVED THE NEGROES
- THE NEGROES SUCCEEDED IN ACCOMPLISHING
WHAT CAVOUR NEVER MANAGED TO DO
- MAKING ITALIANS
- AFTER 300 WE FOUND OURSELVES
ALL BROTHERS GIVING IT TO THE NEGRO
- BUT I REMEMBER
- I REMEMBER
- HOW MUCH YOU DISGUSTED US
- AND YOU CAN TELL THAT WE DIDN'T SAY IT WELL ENOUGH
- WE WEREN'T ABLE TO
TO COMMUNICATE IT TO YOU
- WE WEREN'T EFFECTIVE
- BECAUSE IF YOU HAD UNDERSTOOD,
HOW MUCH WE DESPISED YOU
- NOW YOU WOULD NEVER HAVE VOTED
SALVINI
- YOU WOULD NEVER HAVE HAD THE COURAGE
TO EVEN NOMINATE HIM SECRETARY OF STATE
- BUT INSTEAD...
- TERRONI?
- TERRONI? WHAT'S YOUR FUCKING PROBLEM?
- YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED
- US TOO
- US TOO, WE SHOULD BE ASHAMED
- TO HAVE HAD SUCH GUTTER THOUGHTS
- FINE
- AS LONG AS YOU'RE HAPPY
- IT WAS ONLY A THOUGHT
- BECAUSE I HEARD TWO OLDER FOLKS
WITH SOUTHERN ACCENTS
- SAYING THOSE NEGROES
- ARE ALL DRUG DEALERS
- THAT WE NEED TO KILL THEM ALL
- SO DISAPPOINTING
- FINE
- GOOD NIGHT, NAPLES
- TAKE CARE (WITH FAKE SOUTHERN ACCENT)